A Guide to the W. W. LaPrade and Brothers Records, 1803-2001 (bulk 1900-1970)
Library of Virginia
- Series X. Field Book/Diaries, 1901-2000., Extent: 156 boxes. (Box 189-344)
  - Unidentified, 1941. (Box 342)
  - Unidentified, 1941. (Box 343)
  - Unidentified, 1941. (Box 343)
  - Unidentified, 1949-1953. (Box 343)
  - Unidentified, n.d.. (Box 343)
  - Unidentified, 1941. (Box 343)
  - Time Book/Diary, 1917-1918. (Box 343)
  - Time Book/Diary, 1935-1936. (Box 343)
  - Time Book/Diary, 1941. (Box 343)
  - Time Book/Diary, 1946-1947. (Box 343)
  - Time Book/Diary, 1947. (Box 343)
  - Time Book/Diary, 1952. (Box 343)
  - Time Book/Diary, 1955. (Box 343)
  - Time Book/Diary, circa 1960. (Box 343)
  - Field Book Index, circa 1935-1966. (Box 344)
- Series XI. Computation Books, circa 1945-1972., Extent: 34 boxes. (Box 345-379)
  The Computation Books are housed in thirty-four (34) archival boxes on shelf and arranged numerically by book number with unnumbered books organized at the end roughly by date, if discernible. Some computation book volumes have indexes on front cover, however, there is no cumulative index to computation books. These volumes contain the surveyors' mathematical calculations for jobs using data that they gathered in the field in the field books (Series X).
  - Books 1-3, 3A-9, 13-14, circa 1945-1947. (Box 345)
    Box contains three folders of loose materials found in various volumes.
  - Books 15-22, circa 1946-1947. (Box 346)
  - Books 23-27, 29-35, circa 1946-1948. (Box 347)
  - Books 36-44, circa 1943-1945. (Box 348)
  - Books 45-52, circa 1941-45. (Box 349)
  - Books 53-59, circa 1948-1949. (Box 350)
  - Books 60-67, circa 1948-1949. (Box 351)
  - Books 68-75, circa 1949-1950. (Box 352)
  - Books 76, Index Books 1-57, 77-81, circa 1949-1950. (Box 353)
  - Books 82-88, circa 1949-53. (Box 354)
  - Books 89-92, 92A, 93-94, circa 1950-1952. (Box 355)
  - Books 95-102, circa 1951-1959. (Box 356)
  - Books 103-110, circa 1952-1953. (Box 357)
  - Books 111-113, 115-119, circa 1952-1953. (Box 358)
  - Books 120-127, circa 1954-1957. (Box 359)
  - Books 128-135, circa 1954-1959. (Box 360)
  - Books 136-142, circa 1954-1956. (Box 361)
  - Books 143-145, 147-150, circa 1956-1957. (Box 362)
  - Books 151-155, 157-159, circa 1956-1959. (Box 363)
  - Books 160-166, circa 1953-1959. (Box 364)
    Book 162 contains rough index of field books, 1953-1957.
  - Books 167-171, 173-175, circa 1958-1959. (Box 365)
  - Books 176-183, circa 1958-1960. (Box 366)
  - Books 184, 187-193, circa 1959-1961. (Box 367)
  - Books 195, 197, 199-201, 203-205, circa 1953-1961. (Box 368)
  - Books 207-214, circa 1960-1963. (Box 369)
  - Books 215-220, 222-223, circa 1961-1963. (Box 370)
  - Books 224-227, 229-231, circa 1962-1964. (Box 371)
  - Books 232-238, circa 1964-1965. (Box 372)
  - Books 239-244, 246-247, circa 1964-1967. (Box 373)
  - Books 248, 250-251, 253-256, 258-259, circa 1965-1967. (Box 374)
  - Books 260-262, 264-268, 270, circa 1966-1967. (Box 375)
  - Books 271-274, 276-278, 281, circa 1966-1967. (Box 376)
  - Books 283-284, 287-288, 295, 297-298, 301, circa 1967-1972. (Box 377)
  - Books 302, 304-309, circa 1971-1972. (Box 378)
  - Unnumbered Calculation Books, circa 1934-1966. (Box 379)
- Series XII. Volumes, circa 1872-1949., Extent: 2 boxes (3 volumes). (Box 380-381)
  This consists of three plat books created in part by work of the LaPrade Brothers firm. The volumes have been boxed and/or wrapped for protection. In the case of the Chesterfield Surveyor's Book, circa 1872-1949, loose sheets have been foldered, labled, and boxed with the volume.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Chesterfield Surveyor's Book, circa 1872-1949. (Box 380)
    This volume is intermittent in its entries. Includes Virginia Land Office Treasury Warrants at the end of the volume. Also included is a partial index to the volume.
  - Richmond and Chesapeake Bay Railway Co., Real Estate Record, circa 1905-1907. (Box 381)
    Includes Richmond, Henrico Co., and Ashland (Hanover Co.). Gives description of railroad parcels including deed book citations and small plat drawings.
  - Plat Book No.__, 1926. (Box 381)
    Subtitled "Maps of Property Belonging to Three States Realty Co. and Property to be Conveyed to Virginia Electric and Power in the Appomattox Basin West of Petersburg, Virginia. Prepared April 26, 1926, by W. W. LaPrade and Bros., C.E. and Surveyors, Richmond, Virginia."
  - Books, 1907, 1919. (Box 382)
    "American Highway Engineers' Handbook," edited by Arthur H. Blanchard. (NY: John Wiley & Sons, Inc., 1919) and "Handbook of Cost Data for Contractors and Engineers," by Halbert P. Gillette (NY: McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1907).
  - B.W. LaPrade stamps. (Box 383)